{
  "reference_number": "12391",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The Government need set no emissions targets at all, as emissions have a negligible effect on the climate. According to NIWA, NZ\n\n temperatures have been rising at about 0.01 degree per year for 100 years. The rest of the world is similar. According to Stats NZ, the\n sea level has been rising at a negligible 1.5mm per year for 100 years."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No target is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around the world.."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No target is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around the world.."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "No target is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No emissions budget is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around\n\n the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "No emissions budget is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around\n the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "No emissions budget is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around\n the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Scientific knowledge about climate change must be taken into account. The present government scientific advisers have not done\nso."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No emissions budget is necessary as emissions are not significantly changing the climate, according to plenty of scientists around\nthe world."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The Government must NOT send any money overseas in an attempt to pay for \"carbon credits\". If money is available to be wasted in\n\nthat way, it should be spent on making streams cleaner."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I fear that the present Climate Change Commission are not capable of advising on scientific matters. Their assertions that CO2 and\n\nMethane are changing the climate is wrong, according to plenty of scientists around the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The NZ Emissions Trading Scheme should be abandoned, as it is based on the nonsense that CO2 and Methane have a significant\neffect on climate, when they don't, according to plenty of scientists around the world."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The Climate Change Commission should get advice from overseas experts who are sceptical that CO2 and Methane have a\n\nsignificant effect on climate."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The term Zero Carbon presupposes that Carbon is a bad thing, when in fact CO2 is a colourless trace gas essential for all life on\n\nEarth. 99.9% of all carbon is now contained in limestone and sediments at the bottom of the sea. It is nonsense to try to minimise the\ntiny amount of carbon elsewhere."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "NZ should abandon support of the Paris Agreement. NZ should monitor and mitigate erosion on coastlines"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "More accurate information is needed on potential inundation from storm events. Auckland has had only three major flooding events\n(1936, 2011 and 2018). Some poorly built roads have sunk and become flooded. They should be fixed. Poor drainage needs to be\n\nfixed. None of that is anything to do with Zero Carbon."
    }
  ]
}
